It's useless to try and find him myself...
Maybe I'll ask the guild to
send out search parties.
This knock...
But why isn't he just coming in?
Something must've happened.
Well, as long as you're alive...
that's all I care about.
Lorraine...
Lorraine... wake up.
I said wake up!
Let me sleep just a little more...
I'll drop a book on your head.
Please don't do that...
Rentt... What happened?
As you know, I study monsters and magic.
The Undead
Infiltrates the Town
But I've never heard of anyone who got eaten
by a dragon and turned into an undead.
Is this "dragon" still in the labyrinth?
I think it's gone...
I'm not sure I believe a word
of what you're saying...
But I don't think I have a choice,
given the way you look right now.
Even seeing me like this,
she's completely calm.
That's Lorraine for you. Academic,
mage, and adventurer.
Though it feels like she's viewing me as less
of a friend and more of a test subject...
Rentt.
I know this is a cruel thing
to say, but are you...
Are you, now that you're
undead, really Rentt Faina?
I have the memories and mind of Rentt Faina.
But I definitely died.
Are the current me and the
old me the same person?
I don't know.
That answer seems like exactly
what I'd expect Rentt to say.
But it's hard to say if you're
really the same person.
But we'll set that problem aside for
the moment. I'll think about it later.
So, what will you do now?
I want to continue being an adventurer.
I'm going to become mythril, no matter what.
But I can't go to the guild like this.
So you want me to accept
jobs for you, right?
Oh, you can't use the inn either, can you?
Stay here, then.
I appreciate it, but...
Are you sure?
It doesn't bother me in the slightest.
But I'm sure you'd feel awkward if
I offered to let you stay for free.
So instead, you can help with my research.
No one's ever had the chance
to study a monster that can
use existential evolution directly.
You can't dissect me or anything.
What kind of monster do you take me for?
Well, I might ask for some
skin and flesh, though.
Rentt, I'm back.
Thanks.
Here's the money for the magic stones.
And this is the money for the slime liquid.
You'll pay this much?
If I pay you directly, I can
cut out the guild's fee.
And the materials you bring in
are always of high quality.
They make for great beauty lotions.
Okay, thanks...
I'm off to the Three-Pronged Spear.
The blacksmith?
Yeah.
Few things in life feel
as nice as a heavy purse.
Welcome!
Sorry I look so... strange.
No, don't let it bother you at all.
Come closer. May I ask what brings you here?
I want a new sword.
Let me take a look.
It seems like you've been
taking good care of it,
but it's at the limit of its lifespan.
From the look of the damage, I assume
you either use magic or spirit energy?
Yes, I use both.
And divinity, too.
All of them? That's very rare.
You're only the second such
person to ever visit our store.
If you could keep it a secret...
Of course!
You can't be a blacksmith if you
can't keep your customers' secrets.
Will this be enough?
Yes. We should be able to
make something quite nice.
Feel free to just pay half for the moment.
You can pay the remainder
when you pick it up.
That would be wonderful.
I'm afraid, however,
that the owner, Clope,
takes a great deal of pride in his work.
It will take several days to do the work,
and he'll probably want to speak with you
several times throughout the process.
That's fine...
When you want to see me,
contact Lorraine, the academic.
Very well.
A ghoul... a lesser undead.
Strong physical abilities, and capable
of surviving even decapitation.
They prefer the meat of
animals, particularly humans.
Mostly found in the labyrinths.
Some theories say they are
born from human corpses.
There are known cases of powerful monsters
turning humans into lesser undead.
But in those cases, the victims not
only lost their personalities,
they lost any kind of
human will or emotion...
Rentt is an extremely special
case. So I can't be sure, yet.
But the chance that he's the exact same
being he was in life is extremely low.
But...
He feels like Rentt to me.
He's always...
Missy!
Yes?
You just took a job that'll send
you to Azul Forest, right?
Take him with you as your pack bearer, then.
Nah, you don't have to pay him.
He's an iron-class. A rookie.
I'd like you to help him
gain some experience.
The leaves look different...
This isn't it, either.
Maybe the texts were wrong.
The world was such a boring
place to me back then.
Even when I became the youngest person
to ever attain the title of Great Doctor,
it meant nothing to me.
The title of Great Doctor allows one to
register as a silver-class adventurer.
I went to the frontier nation of Yarlan
without saying a word to anyone around me.
Ostensibly, I was there to
gather some herbs I wanted.
But in fact, I just had
nothing better to do.
This is it!
You need to harvest the root
too, or it's less effective.
I need to be careful...
Hey, pack bearer!
Put this in the pack for me!
Hey, you can't just—
How did you know how to harvest these?
Use Fortia Polivus!
Incredible...
I guess a silver-rank has magic
on a whole other level...
No, it's nothing special...
Here.
Was that your first battle?
Of course not.
But I always had lots of escorts,
or at least people with me...
Don't tell me you...
You didn't seem very experienced
for a silver-class.
So everyone got worried and
told me to follow you.
I see...
You know a lot about herbs, don't you?
Someone once told me that if
I wanted to be an adventurer,
I should learn to read and write,
and about plants, monsters,
and anything else I could.
Hey, I didn't get your name.
Oh, I'm Rentt.
Rentt Faina.
Lorraine Vivie.
Nice to meet you, Lorraine.
Hey...
Could you teach me, too?
About herbs, and how to fight...
You knew exactly how to move
through the forest, too.
There's some trick to it, right?
Well, I don't mind...
There's so much I want to know!
That's how things began
between me and Rentt.
He kept working hard every single
day for the next 10 years,
aiming to become mythril-class.
And I stayed by his side,
doing the research I loved.
That was all I wanted.
Well, I did change, a little.
I can see, looking back, why the
adults were worried about me.
I just realized I've been
lax about replying to letters.
I don't want another
lecture from the old men.
I'll have to ask Rentt where I put them...
Thanks for making a new sword for me.
Yeah, I'll make sure it's something special.
Thanks.
Use this until your sword is ready.
It can use magic and spirit energy.
Nothing else.
Got it.
Looks like he's in a good bit of trouble.
Why doesn't he come to us for help?
Are we that untrustworthy?
I'm guessing that's a curse
he's suffering from.
It's probably a nasty one. One
he thinks might affect our shop.
How awful...
He doesn't like to cause
trouble for other people.
But still, he said some things that
would help us realize who he is, right?
He did. That he could use all types of power,
and that he was staying with Lorraine.
Right?
We can make him tell us
the truth eventually.
It does look like he's going
to keep coming to our shop.
Yes.
It's delicious!
It's been too long since
you've cooked for me!
There's more if you want it.
Sure.
You're not eating?
I don't get hungry.
I see...
Good, then.
Rentt, while you were out, I
read over all my books again.
It's clear that you're different
from an ordinary ghoul.
That's probably got something to do with
the reason you can existential evolve...
What will you become next?
I don't know.
But I want to be as close to human as I can.
I guess that's the first step.
And for that, I'll aim for my
next existential evolution.
Then it's back to the
labyrinth for a while.
Yeah. I'll defeat monsters and get stronger.
No, I was just thinking that
you really don't change.
Damn it!
You okay?
Y-Yeah!
Thanks, you saved my life.
I didn't expect a slime
to attack like that...
I got a little cut. It's
nothing bad, though.
Hey!
Adventurers are expected to be
responsible for themselves.
If you die in the labyrinth, it's
your fault, no matter what.
No one is obligated to help
an adventurer in a bad spot.
Hey, wait!
There are even awful people out there
who'll pretend to be in trouble and rob
adventurers who come to help them,
though they're rare in Maalt.
You're strong, aren't I?
I still always try to save
as many as I can, but...
Please! Let me join your party!
I need... I need the money.
As you can see, I just
registered as an adventurer.
I can't even fight a slime!
Slimes are strong.
Th-They are?
They're hard for swordsmen to fight.
So you are a veteran, aren't you?
I'm a chef. I've got a restaurant in Maalt.
But I'm badly in debt, and I need
to repay 15 gold by next week.
I figured I've got no choice but to take
a chance and become an adventurer.
I told everybody that I'd do whatever they
wanted, as long as they let me in their party.
But nobody would give me a chance.
So I came here, since they said you
could go into this labyrinth alone.
That's only if you're
actually kind of strong...
Sorry, but I'm busy.
I'd love to help him, but unless he got
really lucky and found a magic item...
Wait.
Hey.
You can come with me after all.
I assume you can at least carry a pack.
Wait! You're sure?
Yeah.
Hooray!
I don't know if he's a good guy or not,
but it won't hurt to try
and help someone out.
I'm pretty strong, you know.
I'll do whatever you need.
Sometimes I get really scared...
Am I really me?
Are you, now that you're
undead, really Rentt Faina?
This isn't good...
Hey, this is a dead end, right?
Just follow me.
Huh? There's a corridor.
The map says it's a dead end.
Let's go.
You're kidding me...
There's a place like this down here in
the Labyrinth of the Moon's Reflection?
No dragon, huh?
I figured there'd be a
magic item or two, but...
Hey, I found a little gap over here!
A hidden passage?
Hey, wouldn't we make a fortune
if we told the guild about this?
N-No, I mean, of course I know
you're the one who found it!
I just followed you here.
There's no way I could take the credit.
I'm not interested in glory.
Tell everyone you found it.
But come on ahead with me.
Damn it! Another empty room?
Let's look for secret passages.
Nobody's come here. There should
be at least a treasure or two.
Wait!
Hey!
It's fine!
There are no monsters here or anything.
He can't see it?
Stop!
No...
A teleportation circle...?
Step on a teleportation circle and
you'll be sent somewhere else.
Usually a lower floor filled
with strong monsters,
or some place with deadly traps...
The smart thing to do
would be to abandon him,
but if I do that, I'm just
a monster, aren't I?
Damn it...
Hey!
A giant... skeleton...
A boss room, huh?
Existential Evolution